Inventory of the James A. Bill Papers 1940-2003
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Collection of Interview Transcriptions and Notes, 1951-1994
  - George Ball Notes (2)
    - (2, 10)
      - George Ball Finance Information (2, 10, 8)
        - (2, 10, 8)
          - Letter to George Ball from Theodore S. Peyton, Peyton Associates Realtors, 2/17/1994 (2, 10, 8)
          - Letter to George Ball from John T. Henderson Realtors, 3/10/1994 (2, 10, 8)
          - New York Notes on Weiksner Meeting about Ball finances, 2/23/1994 (2, 10, 8)
        Subseries 9: George Ball manuscript: New Book on Fin De Siencle
      - George Ball manuscript: New Book on Fin De Siencle (2, 10, 9)
        - Manuscript (or a portion of) Ball last book on Fin de Siecle, 5/9/1994 (2, 10, 9)
        Subseries 10: Other Information Referring to George Ball
      - Other Information Referring to George Ball (2, 10)
        - (2, 10)
          - Testimony of George Ball before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee Concerning an Inquiry into the Organization of the Government for the Formulation and Conduct of Foreign Policy, with a Particular Emphasis on the Implications of the End of the Cold War, Washington, DC, 11/6/1991with a copy of a newspaper article: Open Letter to Ed Muskie, by former undersecretary of state in The Washington Post, 5/5/1980 (2, 10)
          - [Bill] Questions for Ball 3/12/1993 with handwritten notes (2, 10)
          - Excerpt from John Dumbrell The Carter Presidency: A Re-evaluation (Manchester: Manchester University Press, 1993) (2, 10)
          - Declassified Files of Telcon, McCloy and Ball, 9/27/1965 (2, 10)
          - Declassified Files of Telcon, McCloy and Ball,10/4/1965 (2, 10)
          - Handwritten notes of a timeline between 1980s and 1990s (2, 10)
          - Handwritten notes on George Ball tapes (2, 10)
          - Excerpt from Bill interview with George Springsteen, 11/12/91 (2, 10)
        Subseries 11: Articles by Ball on Iran and Responses to Ball Articles
      - Articles by Ball on Iran and Responses to Ball Articles (2, 10, 11)
        - (2, 10, 11)
          - George Ball in Familiar Mideast Role in Oil Daily, December 8, 1978(?) (2, 10, 11)
          - U.S. Envoy in Iran Opposed Decision to Aid Dependents Departures, New York Times, pg 3, December 9, 1978 (2, 10, 11)
          - Letter to Delphine Blachowicz 6/6/1979 with letter to George Ball from Delphine Blachowicz, 4/16/1979 concerning Washington Star article. (2, 10, 11)
          - Iran Revolution Isnt Over Yet: George Ball Reports: The New Peril At The Oil Crossroads with Iran: Khomeini Flag of Convenience No Longer Binds and photo of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, The Washington Star, 03/15/1979 (2, 10, 11)
          - Mideast Policy Lessons From Iran: George Ball Reports: The New Peril At the Oil Crossroads Series with Iran: Reliance on Oil States Makes U.S. Policy Vulnerable, The Washington Star 03/17/1979 (2, 10, 11)
          - Iran Coming Backlash by George Ball, New York Times, 5/27/1979 (2, 10, 11)
          - 2 Copies of A Violation of Principle by George Ball, with A Disregard of Religion by Mowahid H. Shah, The Washington Post 11/21/1979 (2, 10, 11)
          - Copy of A Violation of Principle by George Ball in The Washington Post in The Guardian 12/9/1979 (2, 10, 11)
          - Iran Future is Bleak by George Ball in The Washington Post, 8/19/1981 (2, 10, 11)
          - Letter to editor of The Washington Post from John W. Limbert on Ball article on Iran 8/25/1981 (2, 10, 11)
        Subseries 12: Letters and Responses from various individuals to George Ball articles and ideas
      - Letters and Responses from various individuals to George Ball articles and ideas (2, 10, 12)
        - (2, 10, 12)
          - Hand written letter from Solomon (?) Stanger, 2/17/1983 (2, 10, 12)
          - Handwritten letter from John Ray Lackey, date unknown (2, 10, 12)
          - Handwritten letter from Curtis D. Talley(?), date unknown (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from Rabbi Dov Rapaport, 10/5/1985 with copy of Ball response to earlier letter by Rapaport, 12/28/1984 and postcard from Dov Rapaport, 10/7/1985 (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from A.H. Sakier, 10/16/1984 (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from K.S. Judge, 7/14/1982 with Letter from K.S. Judge to Morris Abram, 7/13/1982 and Christians, Jews and Muhabbaadans: Excerpts from Address Delivered at Temple Emmanu-El, San Francisco, 10/12/1912, second edition, BahaI Publications Committee: Wilmette, Illinois, 1940. (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from Bernard Brodsky, with letter to General Sharon(?), (date unknown) (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from Eleanor A. Laury, The Partition of North America and Related Historical Trivia, 5/27/1982 (2, 10, 12)
            - Commentary on: Free to Choose, a television series hosted by Milton Friedman (2, 10, 12)
            - Letter to the American Bible Society, The First Six Hundred Years of The Christian Church" (2, 10, 12)
          - Photocopy of two letters to Aroxie Kalayjian from Charles W. Yost, (top)date unknown, (bottom)3/26/1981 (2, 10, 12)
            - Letter from Aroxie Kalayjian to George Ball, 7/7/1982 (2, 10, 12)
            - Letter from Shulamit Nardi, on behalf of the president Navon of Israel, 5/24/1981 (2, 10, 12)
            - Letter from Department of University Relations and Communications to George Ball, 10/31/1980 (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter from Bill Moldoff, n.d. (2, 10, 12)
          - Divert Aid for Israel To Rebuild Lebanon, George W. Ball,(origin and date unknown) (2, 10, 12)
          - Article Israeli Pilot Tells of Great Effort to Spare Civilians, James Feron, New York Times, (date unknown) (2, 10, 12)
          - College Proficiency Examination of European History (AP) pamphlet (2, 10, 12)
          - Met Museum Given Major Private Collection by Michael Brenson (2, 10, 12)
          - Newspaper Photo of President Reagan endorsing George Deukmejian for Republican Candidate for Governor, New York Times, (date unknown). (2, 10, 12)
          - Newspaper Photo Two Boys Rescued After Arizona Downpour, Associated Press, (date unknown) (2, 10, 12)
          - Book Excerpt, pg. Gibraltar, 11/6/1942(163)-Preparation for Invasion(164) (2, 10, 12)
          - News is Hard to Come By on a Soviet Press Tour, John F. Burns, New York Times, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 12)
          - Newspaper Article Chile Vs. Rights, Felice D. Gaer, (origin and date unknown) (2, 10, 12)
          - Letter to the Editor of New York Times from Jesse Helms, Helms on Prayer and Abortion: I am Ready to Take My Chances, 8/20/1982 (2, 10, 12)
          - Taxes and Taiwan: Some See a Move to the Left, Hendrick Smith, New York Times, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 12)
          - Richmond Admits Guilt, Quits Congress, (author unknown), New York Times, 8/26/1982 (on back) Richmond, a Wealthy Businessman, First Entered Politics as a Reformer, Maurice Caroll, New York Times, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 12)
          - Chapter and Verse: A Correspondence Corner for Not-So-Famous Lost Words, Harvard Magazine, (date/volume unknown) (2, 10, 12)
        Subseries 13: Letters to Ball Criticizing His Op-Ed Piece on Iran/Lebanon 1982
      - Letters to Ball Criticizing His Op-Ed Piece on Iran/Lebanon 1982 (2, 10, 13)
        - (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Bernard Gordin, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Former Admirer of George Ball, 8/26/1982 with Divert Aid for Israel to Rebuild Lebanon, New York Times, 8/25/1982(?) (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Mrs. Jerry Schneider, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from B. Gutchin, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Norma Freedman, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Abraham H. Sakier, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Leonard Harrison, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Divert Aid for Israel to Rebuild Lebanon, New York Times, 8/25/1982 with Letter titled The Roots of Mein Kampf are in the Bible, author unknown (2, 10, 13)
          - Photocopied handwritten letter from Theo. Baumrittw(?), 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Benjamin Greenberg of Benjamin Greenberg Certified Public Accountant, 8/27/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Copy of letter to the editor of New York Times from Joseph Gottfried, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Handwritten letter from E.E. Sheldon M.D, (date unknown) (2, 10, 13)
          - Handwritten letter from Wolf Saltzman, 8/23/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Typed and handwritten letter from Bernard Brodsky, (date unknown) (2, 10, 13)
          - Handwritten letter to George Ball,(author unknown), 7/12/1982 (2, 10, 13)
          - Letter from Hirsh Lazaar Silverman, PhD, 8/29/1982 (2, 10, 13)
        Subseries 14: Letters to Ball Supporting His Op-Ed Piece on Iran/Lebanon 1982
      - Letters to Ball Supporting His Op-Ed Piece on Iran/Lebanon 1982 (2, 10, 14)
        - (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from Mrs. Earle J. Starkey, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from John L. McClenahan, M.D., 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from Lois Reamy, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from R. Eugene Curry, 8/24/1982 with an excerpt from Donald Neff, Warriors at Suez, Linden Press/ Simon and Schuster, 1956 and a thank you note to Mr. Ball, 8/27/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from George S. Franklin of The Trilateral Commission (North America), 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from A.J. Meyer of Harvard University Center For Middle Eastern Studies, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from G. E. Kidder Smith, FAIA, 8/27/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from David MacEachron, Japan Society, Inc., 8/27/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Handwritten letter from C. Nolen, 8/31/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from Lois Battle, 8/26/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Handwritten letter from L. Rubin, M.D., 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Handwritten letter from Robert A. MaLecky, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from Abe Ajay, 8/25/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Handwritten letter from Kathleen Rough Weller, 8/28/1982 (2, 10, 14)
          - Letter from Gardner Cowles, 8/10/1982 with copy of An End to U.S. Indulgence of Israel, by George Ball in The Des Moines Register, 8/4/1982 (2, 10, 14)
        Subseries 15: Ruth Ball Diary, 1976-1980
      - Ruth Ball Diary, 1976-1980 (2, 10, 15)
        - (2, 10, 15)
          - Itinerary for European Ball Family Trip, 7/2/1976 (2, 10, 15)
          - Trip to Europe with Gail and Children, Ruth Ball Diary, 7/2-28/1976 (2, 10, 15)
          - Excerpt from Ruth Ball Diary, 5/25-6/28/? (2, 10, 15)
          - Handwritten, Ruth Ball Diary, Vol. 5, pg 57, (entry 65-68) 1976 (cont.) (2, 10, 15)
          - Handwritten, Ruth Ball Diary, Vol. 6, pg 62, (entry 106-113) 1977(cont.) (2, 10, 15)
          - Handwritten, Ruth Ball Diary, Vol. 7, pg,65 (entry 130-134), pgs 68-69 (entry 147-157) 1978 (cont.) (2, 10, 15)
          - Handwritten, Ruth Ball Diary, Vol. 7, pg 76 (entry 199-210-11), 1980 (cont.) (2, 10, 15)
          - Excerpt from Ruth Ball Diary, (dates unknown) (2, 10, 15)
        - Ruth Ball Diary, Trip to Provence: May 1979, 8/21/1979 (2, 10, 15, 16)
        - (2, 10, 15, 17)
          - Copy of Ruth Ball Family History, 12/1/1977- 3/1981, by Ruth Ball (2, 10, 15, 17)
          - Christmas Turkey Gift List, 1989, George Ball (2, 10, 15, 17)
        Subseries 16: Notes on July 21, 1965 Meeting on Vietnam
      - Notes on July 21, 1965 Meeting on Vietnam (2, 10, 16)
        - (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Request for Reproduction of Documents, NSC Memos to the President, 2/5/1992 by J.A. Bill with Memorandum for the President: Vietnam Planning at Close of Business, July 19 1965, 8:25 p.m. (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Photocopy of Meeting on Vietnam, July 21, 1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Handwritten list of various meeting dates and members, 1966-1968 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Copy of Daily Diary of President Lyndon B. Johnson, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified memo to R. McNamara from Vance on Vietnam, seen by Sec. Def. 7/22/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Dean Rusk Itinerary Schedule for 7/21/1967 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Excerpt from the unpublished manuscript by William P. Bundy during 1969-1972 period concerning Vietnam War decisions, Chapter 27, pg 21-33 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified Excerpt, from memoir of Chester L. Cooper, concerning deployment of troops in Vietnam (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified Memorandum For the President from Horace Busby, concerning impressions on Vietnam Discussion, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified Memo. For the President from Horace Busby, concerning Vietnam and the media, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified memo to Ambassadors Taylor and Johnson from Undersecretary Nodis concerning military actions in Vietnam, 6/1/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - James A. Bill request for Meetings notes on Vietnam, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified document from Chester L. Cooper to Secretary of Defense Robert McNamara concerning Vietnam, 7/20/1965 with Declassified documents from Leonard Unger to Secretary of Defense, Robert McNamara concerning additional developments to Vietnam and Subsequent Developments, 7/20/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Telcon Transcript: The President and Ball, 6/22/1965, 10:10 a.m. (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Cabinet Room Meeting, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Declassified Memorandum for the Record, Meeting on Vietnam, 7/21/1965 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Copy Diary Notes page 325- 331 (2, 10, 16, 18)
          - Copy Diary Notes Vol. 7, 1979, p158-164 (2, 10, 16, 18)
        Subseries 17: Concerning Robert McNamara Book In Retrospect and Vietnam
      - Concerning Robert McNamara Book In Retrospect and Vietnam (2, 10, 17)
        - (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Memo to the President from Robert McNamara, 11/1/1967: concerning the war in Vietnam (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - McNamara Vietnam Confessions: We Were Wrong --- Terribly Wrong!, Lt. Col. Robert M. Browman, Ph.D., USAF, ret, Space and Security News, 4/1995, Vol. 12, Number 2, pg 5 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - The Sad Case of Robert McNamara, George Ball, The New York Review of Books, 4/22/1993, Volume XL, Number 8, pg30-36 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Mr. McNamara War, New York Times, ed. Howell Raines (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Book Review: After Long Silence, Stanley Hoffmann, Books, Fall 1995, pg. 550-553: concerning McNamara views on Vietnam (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Handwritten notes Ball Vietnam Arguments with Excerpts from David Halberstam The Best and the Brightest, pgs. 219,234,408,493, 491 and excerpts from other unknown book, The Kennedy Years, unknown author, unknown title, pg 232, The Johnson Years, pg 340, Vietnam Aberration, pg, 408,412, The Decision to Resign, pg 427, The Private Sector, pg 428, From Nixon to Ford to Carter, pg 451. (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - McNamara Writes Vietnam Mea Culpa: Memoirs Break Silence on War, Thomas W. Lippman, The Washington Post, 4/9/1995, Pg A19-20 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Vietnam Was Terribly Wrong: McNamara details clumsy war policy, Mike Mokrzyckl, Daily Press, 4/9/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Book Review: Robert McNamara Faces History and Himself on Vietnam: After decades of silence, memoir brings admission: We were wrong, terribly wrong, Leonard Bushkoff, The Christian Science Monitor, 4/17/1995, pg 13 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - The Other Vietnam Memorial, James Carroll, The Boston Globe, pg 15, 4/18/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - McNamara Reopens the Liberals War: Potomac Watch (?), Paul A. Gigot(?), The Wall Street Journal, 4/21/1995, pg A10 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Double Articles: McNamara Tells Truth, Accepts Consequences, David H. Hackworth, and Press, McNamara Shared Same Vision, Richard Harwood, Unknown Newspaper, pg H3, 7/23/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Double Articles: Surreal Surrender In Vietnam: What I Saw in Ford White House, Ron Nessen, The Washington Post, pg C1, C3, 4/23/1995 and McNamara to World: Moi?, Mary McGrory, The Washington Post, pg C1, C5, 4/23/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Book Reviews: Robert McNamara Private War, Peter Braestrup, The Washington Post: Book World, pg 1, 4/23/1995 and Twenty Years After: Marking An Ending, Jeff Stein, The Washington Post: Book World, pg 9, 4/23/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Vietnam After McNamara, William E. Colby, The Washington Post, pgA21, 4/27/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Robert McNamara Mea Cupa: Letters to the Editor, The Washington Post, pg 20, 4/27/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Mr. McNamara Other War, The Washington Post, pg C6, 4/30/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
          - Book Reviews: Discovering the Quagmire: In the Early 1960, American Journalists in Vietnam Began to Mistrust Their Government. And Visa Versa, H.D.S Greenway, New York Times Book Reviews, 11/19/1995 (2, 10, 17, 19)
        Subseries 18: Letters of Correspondence between George Ball and Associates 1951-1953
      - Letters of Correspondence between George Ball and Associates 1951-1953 (2, 10, 18)
        - (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Governor Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 12/11/1951 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 1/5/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Richard F. Babcock, Esq. from George Ball, 2/17/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Harold C. Havighurst from George Ball, 2/21/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Barry Bingham from George Ball, 2/22/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 2/22/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Carl McGowan, Esq. from George Ball, 2/25/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Dr. Leo Doyle from George Ball, 3/12/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 6/29/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to James G. Johnson, Jr., Esq. from George Ball 7/11/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 7/11/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 7/25/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 7/28/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 11/10/1953 (2, 10, 18, 20)
          - Letter to Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 8/30/1954 (2, 10, 18, 20)
        Subseries 19: Personal Correspondence between George Ball and Acquaintances 1956
      - Personal Correspondence between George Ball and Acquaintances 1956 (2, 10, 19)
        - (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Memorandum on Sugar: concerns US involvement in Cuba (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mr. Neale Roach from George Ball, 1/9/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to David Rockefeller from George Ball, 1/10/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mrs. James F. Howard from George Ball, 1/23/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Hon. Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 3/10/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Major Benjamin H. Namm from George Ball, 4/24/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mr. William Wirtz from George Ball, 5/9/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Ralph K. Ball, Esq. from George Ball, 5/11/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Ralph K. Ball, Esq. from George Ball, 6/5/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Anderson and Sheppard, Ltd. From George Ball, 6/5/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Gov. Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 6/15/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Gov. Adlai E. Stevenson from George Ball, 6/19/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mr. Clayton Fritchey from George Ball, 8/29/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mr. F. deTurckheim with list of names from Miss Florence Roth, Secretary to George Ball, 11/16/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Mr. Irving Jay Fain from George Ball, 11/27/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Letter to Hon. William Benton from George Ball, 12/13/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Telecom Transcript: The President and George Ball, 11/16/1965, 4:45 p.m. (2, 10, 19, 21)
          - Telecom Transcript: Adlai Stevenson Jr. and George Ball, 12/2/1956 (2, 10, 19, 21)
        Subseries 20: Notes concerning George Ball and Adlai Stevenson
      - Notes concerning George Ball and Adlai Stevenson (2, 10, 20)
        - (2, 10, 20, 22)
          - Ball, George, The Past Has Another Pattern: Memoirs, W. W. Norton and Company: 1983, pg 111-151, excerpts concerning Adlai Stevenson and the Campaign of 1956 (2, 10, 20, 22)
          - Two copies of excerpts from unknown book draft by George Ball concerning Adlai Stevenson and George Ball, 12/12/1965 (2, 10, 20, 22)
        - (2, 10, 20, 23)
          - Handwritten notes (2, 10, 20, 23)
          - Excerpt from unknown book by George Ball, concerning 1952 Presidential Campaign and Adalai Stevenson (2, 10, 20, 23)
          - What-If of Adlai Stevenson, by Herbert Mitgang, New York Times, 12/3/1977 (2, 10, 20, 23)
          - Outline for Bill, James, Political Practitioner and Intellectual Gladiator, from George Ball: Behind the Scenes in U.S. Foreign Policy, New Haven: Yale University Press, 1997 (2, 10, 20, 23)
          - Handwritten notes about Adlai Stevenson (2, 10, 20, 23)
        Subseries 21: Articles about George Ball and President Richard Nixon Presidential Policies and His Death
      - Articles about George Ball and President Richard Nixon Presidential Policies and His Death (2, 10, 21)
        - (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Mr. Nixon, Then and Now: Historical Note, 10/5/1956, 11/12/1959, notes concerning Richard Nixon views on H-Bomb testing (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Kilpatrick, Carroll. But Is Critical on Vietnam: Ball Gives Nixon Good Marks For Foreign Policy Conduct. Paris-Herald Tribune (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Montgomery, William. Ex-Diplomat Speaks Here: Nixon Vietnam Phase-out Is Termed Best Alternative. Albuquerque Journal. 11/15/1969 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Roberts, Chalmers M. President Swatted Wrong Ball. The Washington Post, 7/5/1970 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Diplomatic Staff. Nixon China Initiative Symbolic Diplomacy. The Manchester Guardian. 7/20/1971 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Ball, George. George Ball, Former Under-Secretary of State, on the Role of the White House: Watergate, With New Cleansing Power. The Times, 6/11/1973 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Ball, George. Opinion letter. Newsweek. 8/19/1974 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Excerpt from Morvour, William. Witness. 1987 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Carter, Dan T. Richard Nixon Still Has Something to Hide. Los Angeles Herald Examiner. 7/25/1988: pg A11 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - R. Beschloss, Michael. Nixon Other Secret Plan: Above All, He Wanted an Honored Place in History. The Washington Post, 5/1/1994: pg C1,C2 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - W. Lippman, Thomas. After the Eulogies: Nixon Critics Recall Vietnam. The Washington Post. 5/1/1994: pg A 11 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Stone, Roger. Nixon on Clinton. New York Times Op-Ed. 4/28/1994: pg A 23 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - President Bill Clinton. Transcript of Clinton Eulogy for Nixon: He Never Gave Up, New York Times: National, 4/28/1994: pg A 20 (2, 10, 21, 24)
            - Former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger Kissinger Tribute to Nixon: One of the Seminal Presidents. New York Times: National. 4/28/1994: pg A 20 (2, 10, 21, 24)
            - Senator Bob Dole. Senator Dole Remarks on Nixon: He Embodied The Nation Feelings. New York Times: National. 4/28/1994: pg A 20 (2, 10, 21, 24)
          - Albert R. Hunt. ONeil, Nixon and the Importance of Roots: Politics and People. The Wall Street Journal, pg A11, 12/29/1994 (2, 10, 21, 24)
        Subseries 22: Dean Rusk Articles and Notes
      - Dean Rusk Articles and Notes (2, 10, 22)
        - (2, 10, 22, 25)